<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fantasia on AlienCDH</title>
    <link>https://aliencdh.github.io/tags/fantasia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fantasia on AlienCDH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aliencdh.github.io/tags/fantasia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>fantasia - Starting Out</title>
      <link>https://aliencdh.github.io/fantasia-starting-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 20:32:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aliencdh.github.io/fantasia-starting-out/</guid>
      <description>First, let&amp;rsquo;s define some goals:
API-agnostic. The renderer should be a library-type crate that simply provides the necessary tools for rendering into an array of bytes representing pixels. Being API-agnostic would make it very flexible and versatile, allowing its users to adapt to their own specific use cases. Capable of rendering 3D models, of course. That&amp;rsquo;s the main point, after all. As few dependencies as possible. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to complicate ourselves or pick up too much stuff that we don&amp;rsquo;t need.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s define some goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API-agnostic. The renderer should be a library-type crate that simply provides the necessary
tools for rendering into an array of bytes representing pixels.
Being API-agnostic would make it very flexible and versatile, allowing its users to adapt
to their own specific use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capable of rendering 3D models, of course. That&amp;rsquo;s the main point, after all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As few dependencies as possible. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to complicate ourselves or pick up too much stuff that we don&amp;rsquo;t need.
The renderer should be pretty simple in its design and not bring in too many dependencies to whoever might decide to use
it in their project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something you hopefully understand pretty well by the end of this guide. This is more of a goal for me, if anything.
I hope my way of explaining concepts through examples will work for you as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now that that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s set our crate up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cargo new --lib fantasia
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cd fantasia
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For now, I think we should only have 2 dependencies:
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/image&#34;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/wasm-bindgen&#34;&gt;wasm-bindgen&lt;/a&gt; crates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;cargo add image wasm-bindgen
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/wasm-bindgen&#34;&gt;wasm-bindgen&lt;/a&gt; is here to make the renderer usable on the web as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/image&#34;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; is here so that we can more easily test it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fantasia</title>
      <link>https://aliencdh.github.io/projects/fantasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aliencdh.github.io/projects/fantasia/</guid>
      <description>A 3D renderer I decided to write as a practice project, in Rust, with as few dependencies as possible.
When I first thought about starting this project, I was pretty intimidated. I had assumed that renderers are such vastly complicated things that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly hope to understand them. But I found a nice little guide about writing one in C, and I decided to follow it. But rather than just following it in C, I decided to do it in Rust.</description>
      <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 3D renderer I decided to write as a practice project, in Rust, with as few dependencies as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first thought about starting this project, I was pretty intimidated.
I had assumed that renderers are such vastly complicated things that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly hope to understand them.
But I found a nice little guide about writing one in C, and I decided to follow it.
But rather than just following it in C, I decided to do it in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was for 2 simple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to simply be able to copy-paste the parts I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. I wanted to
have to somehow try to understand what was going on before adapting it to Rust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I simply like the safety of Rust, and how it makes it so that I have much fewer things to worry about
than in C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip; The book just didn&amp;rsquo;t work that well for me, no offense to the author.
It explained certain concepts in a way that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand, and sometimes it didn&amp;rsquo;t explain them at all.
So I stumbled around trying my best to come up with my own solutions where I could, until it all started clicking for me.
Hoping to make this process easier for other people, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try and write a guide for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also check out my code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aliencdh/fantasia&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
